Adult Education Association (AEA-USA)/American Association for Adult and Continuing Education (AAACE) Records
Adult Education Association (AEA-USA)/American Association for Adult and Continuing Education (AAACE) Records
- [Part I] Organizational records
  - Proposals
    - Council of National Organizations, 1951 (Box 27)
    - Development and Improvement of Adult Education, 1955 (Box 27)
    - Development of Closer Cooperative Relationships among Adult Educators of the British Commonwealth and the U.S., 1958 (Box 27)
    - Development of Professional Training for Adult Education, 1952 (Box 27)
    - Education for Aging, 1952-1956 (Box 27)
    - Financing Adult Education Study, 1956 (Box 27)
    - Fundamental Education for Adults, 1956 (Box 27)
    - Graduate Studies in Adult Education, 1955-1965 (Box 27)
    - Information Services, 1954-1955 (Box 27)
    - In-Service Training for Adult Educators, 1955-56 (Box 28)
    - Intern Project, 1952-1953 (Box 28)
    - Local Coordination and Field Services, 1953 (Box 28)
    - National Fund for the Promotion of Life-Long Learning, 1955 (Box 28)
    - Personnel Development and In-Service Training in National Organizations, 1958 (Box 28)
    - Personnel Information Exchange, 1955 (Box 28)
    - Planning Facilities for Adult Education, 1953 (Box 28)
    - Projecting the Role of a National Organization in the Development of Adult Education as an Integral Part of Our Nation's System of Education, 1959? (Box 28)
    - Promotional Policy, 1955 (Box 28)
    - Relationships of Adult Educators Study, 1955 (Box 28)
    - Services to Public Schools, 1956 (Box 28)
    - Social Trends Affecting Adult Education, 1956 (Box 28)
    - Strengthening Adult Education Leadership in the 1960's, 1961 (Box 28)
    - Study Groups on the Meaning of Adult Education in American Life, 1951 (Box 28)
    - World-Wide Adult Education Workshop and Field Study Project, 1954 (Box 28)
  - Publications
    - Adult Leadership
      - Report of first year, 1952 (Box 28)
      - Study, 1953 (Box 28)
      - Project report, 1954 (Box 28)
    - Adult Leadership, 1962-1963 (Box 28)
    - Editorial programs of Adult Leadership and Adult Education, 1956 (Box 28)
    - General adult education brochure, undated (Box 28)
    - "Illustrations That Stick", 1954 (Box 28)
    - Lists of articles, miscellaneous, circa 1967 (Box 28)
    - Newsletters, 1959-1960; 1967; 2 folders (Box 28)
    - Policy, staff organization, and responsibilities, 1955 (Box 28)
    - Press releases and clippings, 1952-1966 (Box 28)
    - Reprints from Adult Education and Adult Leadership, 1952-1955 (Box 28)
    - Staff News Bulletin, 1955-1956 (Box 28)
    - "The Tool Kit", 1952-1953 (Box 28)
  - Reports
    - Annual, 1952; 1954,; 1955,; 1957,; 1960,; 1961; 6 folders (Box 29)
    - Progress, 1952-1953 (Box 29)
  - Sections
    - Armed Forces Education and Training, 1967 (Box 29)
    - Business and industry, 1958-1961 (Box 29)
    - Community Development Division
      - National University Extension Association (NUEA), 1959-1967 (Box 29)
      - National Training Laboratories, 1961-1963 (Box 29)
    - Continuing Education of Clergy, 1967 (Box 29)
    - Continuing Education for the Professions, 1967 (Box 29)
    - Continuing Education for Women, 1967 (Box 29)
    - Correctional Institutions, 1967 (Box 29)
    - Education for the Aging
      - General, 1954-1959 (Box 29)
      - Inventory of projects and programs, 1967; 2 folders (Box 29)
      - Philadelphia Conference, 1967 (Box 29)
      - Report on the National Pilot Institute on Education for the Aging, 1967 (Box 29)
      - United States Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, 1967 (Box 29)
    - Home and Family Life, 1953-1967 (Box 30)
    - International Affairs, 1967 (Box 30)
    - Junior and Community Colleges, 1967 (Box 30)
    - Labor Education, 1967 (Box 30)
    - Liberal Adult Education, 1967 (Box 30)
    - Mass Media in Education, 1967 (Box 30)
    - National Institute of Labor Education Urban Task Force, 1961-1963 (Box 30)
    - Public Affairs, 1967 (Box 30)
    - Religious Adult Education, 1967 (Box 30)
    - Residential Adult Education, 1967 (Box 30)
    - Training, Education and Industry, 1967 (Box 30)
    - Training and Professional Development Adult Education Consultants, 1956 (Box 30)
  - Study of AEA
    - [General], 1953 Nov (Box 30)
    - Four Year Assessment, 1955 (Box 30)
    - [General], 1959; 2 folders (Box 30, 31)
  - Television Discussion Program, undated (Box 31)
  - Staff meeting minutes, 1955-1956 (Box 31)
  - Notebooks
    - Operation Committee meeting minutes, 1951 May-1953 Apr (Box 31)
    - Council of National Organizations News for Adult Education, 1952-1962 (Box 31)
    - Publications Committee meeting minutes, 1952-1953; 4 folders (Box 31)
      1952 Sep 20
      1953 Mar 20
      1953 Apr 10-11
      1953 Nov 21-23
    - Adult Education Association memoranda, 1952; 1953; 2 folders (Box 31)
    - Publication Committee meeting minutes, 1954; 4 folders (Box 31)
      Feb 13-14, Apr 24-25, Sep 16-17, Nov 9
    - Executive Committee meeting, 1954 Apr 2-4 (Box 31)
    - Executive Committee meeting workbook, 1954 Sep 9-11 (Box 32)
    - Adult Education Association Conference on Adult Education, 1954 Nov 7-9 (Box 32)
    - Publication Department, current operating policies, 1955-1959 (Box 32)
    - Public relations material, 1955; undated; 2 folders (Box 32)
    - Publication Committee meeting minutes, 1955; 4 folders (Box 32)
      Jan 8-9, May 8-9, Oct 15-16, Nov 13
    - Executive Committee meeting workbook, 1955 Feb 19-21 (Box 32)
    - Publications Department, current operating policies Adult Leadership, 1955 Apr-Dec (Box 32)
    - Executive Committee meeting workbook, 1955; 2 folders (Box 32)
      May 13-15, Sep 9-11
    - Where Has the AEA Been and Where Should It Go: A Four Year Assessment, 1955 Nov 1 (Box 32)
    - Executive Committee meeting workbook, 1955 Nov 15-17 (Box 32)
    - C.N.O., Public Relations Committee, 1956-1962 (Box 32)
    - An Assessment of the AEA's First Five Years and a Program for the Next Five, Spring, 1956 (Box 32)
    - Executive Committee meetings
      - Workbook A, 1956 Mar 8-11 (Box 32)
      - Workbook B, 1956 Mar 8-11 (Box 32)
    - Publications Committee meeting minutes, 1956 May 17-18 (Box 32)
    - An Analysis of AEA's Administration, 1956 Jul 12 (Box 32)
    - Project Proposal: Major Social Trends Affecting Adult Education, 1956 Oct (Box 32)
    - Roster of Adult Education Councils and Associations, 1956 Nov (Box 32)
    - Adult Education Policies Commission proposal, 1956 Nov 1; appendices 1-5; 2 folders (Box 32)
    - Report of the Consultative Meeting on Direction Finding, 1957 Aug 3-4 (Box 33)
    - Publications Committee meeting minutes, 1957 Nov 13 (Box 33)
    - Council of National Organizations
      - Population Study Proposal, 1959 Mar-Apr (Box 33)
      - Project Development Committee, 1960-1962 (Box 33)
      - Volunteer Staff Relations Committee, 1960-1961 (Box 33)
      - Steering Committee, 1961 Oct 11 (Box 33)
      - Television and Radio Committee, 1962 Mar-May (Box 33)
      - Young Adult Committee, 1962 Mar 27 (Box 33)
      - Planning Committee Meeting, 1962 Mar 28 (Box 33)
      - Reorganization Committee, 1962 May 4 (Box 33)
      - Proposal to the Fund for Adult Education from the AEA, undated; preliminary draft (Box 33)
      - Publication Department current operating policies, department files, undated (Box 33)
  - AEA Publication Notes, undated (Box 33)
- [Part I] Writings
  - Articles
    - Burr, Elbert W., "Values of AEA Membership", 1958 Apr (Box 33)
    - Knowles, Malcolm S., "The Group Process in Adult Education", undated (Box 33)
    - Luke, Robert A., "The Cost of Adult Under-Education", 1956 Oct (Box 33)
    - Luke, Robert A., "The Purposes of the AEA as They Relate to the Populations It May Serve,", 1957 (Box 33)
    - Stevenson, Grace T., "AEA's Responsibilities in a World of Change", 1958 Jan (Box 33)
    - Stevenson, Grace T., "Origins of the Community Adult Education Council Idea,", undated (Box 33)
  - Book reviews, ca. 1958 (Box 33)
  - Copy
    - Adult Education
      - Miscellaneous, 1958, Apr-Nov; 2 folders (Box 33)
      - Miscellaneous, 1958, Sep - 1959, Jan (Box 33)
      - Miscellaneous, 1959 (Box 33)
      - Advertising Copy, 1959 (Box 33)
      - Miscellaneous, 1959 Mar-Aug (Box 33)
    - Adult Leadership
      - Miscellaneous, 1955, Fall (Box 34)
      - Miscellaneous, 1956, Fall (Box 34)
      - Miscellaneous, 1957, Fall (Box 34)
      - Future issues, 1958 (Box 34)
      - Miscellaneous, 1957, Mar-Dec; 2 folders (Box 34)
      - Miscellaneous, 1958, Spring, Winter; 2 folders (Box 34)
      - Miscellaneous, 1959-1960 (Box 34)
      - Miscellaneous, 1959; 1963 (Box 34)
      - Miscellaneous, 1959, Jan-Sep; 4 folders (Box 34)
      - Miscellaneous, 1959, Oct-Dec; 2 folders (Box 35)
      - Miscellaneous, 1962, Fall (Box 35)
      - Miscellaneous, 1964, Mar-Dec (Box 35)
      - Miscellaneous, 1965; 2 folders (Box 35)
      - Miscellaneous, 1966; 2 folders (Box 35)
  - Speeches
    - Arnold, Mrs. Dexter Otis "Assignment for the Sixties: To Strengthen the Arm of Liberty", 1962 Jul 5 (Box 35)
    - Blakely, Robert J. "Adult Education Needs a Philosophy and a Goal", 1952 Oct (Box 35)
    - Dale, Edgar, "Something to Grow On", 1958 Nov 18 (Box 35)
    - Darley, Dr. Ward "The Implications of Population Trends to Health", 1956 (Box 35)
    - Durrie, Paul H. Address at National Conference, 1952 (Box 35)
    - Fletcher, C. Scott "The Free University or Liberal Arts College: Its Role in Education for Freedom and Responsibility", 1961 Feb 20 (Box 35)
    - Hanna, John A. Address at National Conference, 1952 (Box 35)
    - Holden, John B. "Wanted! More Community Representatives", 1954 Dec 1 (Box 35)
    - Houle, Cyril O. "Developing Goals for Public School Adult Education", 1959 Nov 4 (Box 35)
    - Jensen, Glenn Ideas for Presidential Address, 1963 (Box 35)
    - McMurrin, Sterling M. Statement Before the Sub-Committee on Education, Committee on Labor and Public Welfare, U.S. Senate, 1962 July 27 (Box 35)
    - Weaver, John C. "The Facts and Philosophy of Graduate Extension Education,", 1958 Nov 10 (Box 35)
- [Part II]
  - Activities
    - Adult Basic Education Regional Conferences Project, 1965-1966 (Box 36)
    - Adult Basic Education Survey Project, 1970-1971; 21 folders (Box 36)
    - American Indian Development, 1950s; 23 folders (Box 36)
    - Latin America Adult Education Survey, 1965; 66 folders (Box 37, 38)
    - National Adult and Continuing Education Week, 1985-1986; 1988; 21 folders (Box 38)
  - Affiliations
    - Ad Hoc National Advisory Organizations - Advisory Committee on Consumer Interests (Box 38)
    - Adult Education Association of Greater Washington, D.C. (Box 38)
    - Adult Education Association of Greater Washington, D.C., 5 folders (Box 39)
    - Coalition of Adult Education Organizations, 1974-1975 (Box 39)
  - Annual Reports, 1951-1982; 29 folders (Box 39)
  - Board of Directors, 1983-1988; 9 folders (Box 39)
  - Budgets, 1958-1963; 6 folders (Box 39)
  - Commissions
    - Adult Basic Education, 1966-1972; 2 folders (Box 39)
    - Adult Basic Education, 1973-1974; 1983-1986; 2 folders (Box 40)
    - Minority Groups, 1974 (Box 40)
    - National Commission for Adult Literacy, 1956-1967 (Box 40)
    - Planning Adult Learning Systems, Facilities and Environments, 1968-1974; 4 folders (Box 40)
    - Professors of Adult Education, 1964-1970; 1983-1984; 3 folders (Box 40)
    - Research, 1964; 1973,; 1983; 2 folders (Box 40)
    - Status of Women, 1972-1973 (Box 40)
  - Committees
    - Action Now, 1969-1972; 2 folders (Box 40)
    - American Family, 1973-1974 (Box 40)
    - Constitutional Revision, 1970 (Box 40)
    - Consumer Education, 1969-1974 (Box 40)
    - Continuing Education Development Project, 1973 (Box 40)
    - Development, 1977-1983 (Box 40)
    - Executive, 1951-1964; 14 folders (Box 40)
    - Executive, 1965-1982; 23 folders (Box 41)
    - Five Year Goals, 1979 (Box 41)
    - Future Conferences, 1971; 1973-1974; 2 folders (Box 41)
    - Human Rights and Social justice, 1983-1987 (Box 41)
    - Legislative Policies, 1966-1968; 2 folders (Box 41)
    - Legislative Policies, 1969-1971; 1973-1974; 7 folders (Box 42)
    - Long Range Financing, 1973-1974 (Box 42)
    - Mainline, 1969-1970 (Box 42)
    - Membership, 1965-1968; 1970-1974; 5 folders (Box 42)
    - Nominations and Elections, 1967; 1970-1974; 6 folders (Box 42)
    - Nontraditional Study, 1973-1974 (Box 42)
    - Organization Restructuring, 1980 (Box 42)
    - Organizational Renewal, 1973-1974 (Box 42)
    - Personnel Policies, undated (Box 42)
    - Public Information, 1974 (Box 42)
    - Publications, 1966-1968; 1970,; 1973-1974; 4 folders (Box 42)
    - Resolutions, 1970-1974; 2 folders (Box 42)
    - Steering, 1953; 1955-1957,; 1961,; 1963-1964; 7 folders (Box 42)
    - Steering, 1965-1982; 19 folders (Box 43)
  - Conferences
    - Annual, 1958; 1963-1966; 22 folders (Box 43)
    - Annual, 1965-1968; 1973-1975,; 1978,; 1984,; 1986-1987; 17 folders (Box 44)
    - Conference rosters (Box 44)
    - Galaxy Conference, 1969; 8 folders (Box 44, 45)
    - Health Services and Community Organization, 1965 (Box 45)
    - Leadership and Legislative Seminar, 1987-1988; 2 folders (Box 45)
    - Legislative Seminar, 1973 (Box 45)
    - Legislative Workshop, 1974 (Box 45)
    - Metroplex Assembly, 1963-1964 (Box 45)
    - National Adult Education Conference, 1980-1982; 1986; 4 folders (Box 45)
  - Constitutions and bylaws (Box 45)
  - Councils
    - Affiliate organizations, 1973-1974 (Box 45)
    - National organizations for adult education, 1973 (Box 45)
    - State associations, 1963-1969 (Box 45)
  - Delegate Assembly, 1951-1977; 28 folders (Box 45)
  - Delegate Assembly, 1978-1982; 5 folders (Box 46)
  - Directories, 1965; 1981,; 1986; 3 folders (Box 46)
  - Leadership rosters, 1979-1988 (Box 46)
  - Manuals
    - AAACE Development, Proposal, and Consultation, 1983 (Box 46)
    - Development, 1979 (Box 46)
    - Fiscal Policies, 1980 (Box 46)
    - Membership Tips, 1981 (Box 46)
    - Orientation Manual for Leaders, undated (Box 46)
    - Policies and Procedures, 1972 (Box 46)
    - Policy and Procedures, proposed, 1979-1982 (Box 46)
    - Policy and Procedures, 1984-1985; 1988; 2 folders (Box 46)
  - Mission statement, 1986 (Box 46)
  - Publications
    - AEA Reporter, 1978-1980 (Box 46)
    - Federal Support for Adult Education: A Directory, 1966 (Box 46)
    - Handbook of Adult Education, 1970; 2 folders (Box 46)
    - Lifelong Learning, 1980-1983; 4 folders (Box 46)
    - Priorities in Adult Education, 1969-1972 (Box 46)
    - Publications Department Binder (Box 46)
  - Sections
    - Adult Psychology, undated (Box 46)
    - Adult Religious Education, 1969-1973 (Box 46)
    - Armed Forces Education, 1973-1974 (Box 46)
    - Community College, 1974 (Box 46)
    - Community Development, 1973-1974 (Box 46)
    - Continuing Education for the Professions, 1973-1974 (Box 46)
    - Continuing Education for Women, 1973-1974 (Box 46)
    - Correctional Institutions, 1974 (Box 46)
    - Education for Aging, 1973-1976; 3 folders (Box 46)
    - Education for Aging, 1970; 1972-1979; 20 folders (Box 47)
    - Graduate Students, 1970-1974; 1982-1987; 2 folders (Box 47)
    - Home and Family Life Education, 1970-1974 (Box 47)
    - International Affairs, 1970-1974 (Box 47)
    - Labor Education, 1970-1973 (Box 47)
    - Liberal Adult Education, 1970-1973 (Box 47)
    - Mass Media in Adult Education, 1968-1974 (Box 47)
    - Residential, 1966-1970 (Box 47)
    - Training and Professional Development, 1969-1974 (Box 47)
  - Smith, Wendell files
    - Adult Education Foundation, 1981 (Box 48)
    - Annual reports, 1981-1982; 2 folders (Box 48)
    - Articles, 1980-1981; 2 folders (Box 48)
    - Awards, 1981-1982 (Box 48)
    - Board of Directors, 1983; 2 folders (Box 48)
    - Budgets, 1979-1982 (Box 48)
    - Commissions, Committees and Sections, 1978-1983; 21 folders (Box 48)
    - Commissions, Committees and Sections, 1978-1982; 3 folders (Box 49)
    - Conferences, 1973; 1976-1981; 31 folders (Box 49)
    - Conferences, 1980-1982; 40 folders (Box 50)
    - Conferences, 1982-1984; 16 folders (Box 51)
    - Consolidation and Merger, 1981-1982; 21 folders (Box 51)
    - Delegate Assembly, 1976-1979; 4 folders (Box 51)
    - Directory, 1981 (Box 51)
    - Dues, 1980 (Box 51)
    - Elections, 1980-1983; 5 folders (Box 51)
    - Executive Director search and national office staffing, 1980-1982 (Box 51)
    - Fiscal policies, 1981 (Box 51)
    - Ideas, 1981; 1983 (Box 51)
    - Ideological Program Units, 1982 (Box 51)
    - Insurance, 1981 (Box 51)
    - International Council for Adult Education, 1979-1982; 2 folders (Box 51)
    - Leadership Interest Inventory, 1980-1981 (Box 51)
    - Leadership rosters, 1977-1981 (Box 51)
    - Lifelong Learning Leaders Retreat, 1982; 23 folders (Box 51, 52)
    - Luke, Robert, 1981 (Box 52)
    - Membership, 1976-1983 (Box 52)
    - Membership recruitment, 1981-1982 (Box 52)
    - National Association for Public Continuing & Adult Education (NAPCAE), 1981 (Box 52)
    - Policies and Procedures Manual, 1972 (Box 52)
    - Projects, 1973; 1978-1980; 2 folders (Box 52)
    - Proposals, 1980-1981 (Box 52)
    - Publications, 1976-1983; 6 folders (Box 52)
    - Ridlehuber, Tom, 1982 (Box 52)
    - Task Force on Cooperation, 1980-1981 (Box 52)
    - Washington meeting, 1981 (Box 52)
    - Whaples, Gene, 1982-1983 (Box 52)
  - Subject correspondence
    - Aker, George, 1970-1972 (Box 52)
    - Arizona State University Conference, 1968 (Box 52)
    - Arlington County Adult Education Advisory Committee, 1967-1968 (Box 52)
    - Association of Hospital and Institution Libraries, 1966-1967 (Box 52)
    - Benjamin Franklin Living Memorial, 1966-1967 (Box 52)
    - Business correspondence, 1966-1972; 3 folders (Box 52)
    - Business correspondence, 1974; 3 folders (Box 53)
    - Clearinghouse on Adult Education, 1986 (Box 53)
    - COMPACT: Education Study of the American States, 1964-1967 (Box 53)
    - Conference on TV and World Affairs, 1968 (Box 53)
    - Conservation Foundation, 1967 (Box 53)
    - Correspondence schools, 1968 (Box 53)
    - Council for Adult and Experiential Learning (CAEL), 1986 (Box 53)
    - ERIC Clearinghouse / Roger DeCrow, 1967-1969 (Box 53)
    - Evening Student Personnel Association, 1967 (Box 53)
    - Foreign Policy Association, 1967 (Box 53)
    - Higher adult education surveys, 1968 (Box 53)
    - Higher education general information survey, 1967-1969 (Box 53)
    - Hospital libraries, 1964-1967 (Box 53)
    - Johnson, Eugene, 1962-1963 (Box 53)
    - Johnson, Lyndon, 1967 (Box 53)
    - Kellogg Grant, 1982 (Box 53)
    - Kettering Foundation, 1967 (Box 53)
    - Klein, Philip, 1970-1971 (Box 53)
    - Koinonia Foundation, 1967-1968 (Box 53)
    - Literacy Position Paper, 1987 (Box 53)
    - Literacy Summit, 1987 (Box 53)
    - Luke, Robert A., 1981-1982 (Box 53)
    - Martin Luther King Foundation, 1968 (Box 53)
    - Mary Holmes Community College, 1968 (Box 53)
    - Migrant Workers in the State of Washington, 1966-1967 (Box 53)
    - Military / GED, 1987 (Box 53)
    - Mind, Inc., 1967 (Box 53)
    - Mott Foundation, 1986-1987 (Box 53)
    - National Association of Trade and Technical Schools, 1967-1968 (Box 53)
    - NAPSAE / ABE Clearinghouse, 1967-1969 (Box 53)
    - National Governors' Association Task Force on Adult Literacy, 1986-1987 (Box 53)
    - National Research Conference on Smoking Behavior, 1966 (Box 53)
    - National Rural and Small Schools Consortium, 1986 (Box 53)
    - National Science Foundation Proposal, 1966 (Box 53)
    - New Institutional Forms for Adult Education / Roy Ingham, 1966 (Box 53)
    - New Jersey Adult Leadership Institute, 1968 (Box 53)
    - Office of Economic Opportunity Proposal, 1967 (Box 53)
    - Pacific Northwest Council on Theological Education, undated (Box 53)
    - Pagano, Jules / Congratulatory Letters, 1969-1970 (Box 53)
    - Proposal for World Conference of Directors of Adult Associations in Hawaii, 1967 (Box 53)
    - Sackett, Duane H., 1971 (Box 53)
    - Satellite television, 1966-1967 (Box 53)
    - Sork, Thomas J., 1978-1979; 2 folders (Box 53)
    - Symposium on Communities of Tomorrow (USDA), 1967 (Box 53)
    - Technical Advisory Committee on Adult Literacy, 1966-1967 (Box 54)
    - Tidewater Regional Conference, 1967-1968 (Box 54)
    - Town and Country Alliance, 1968 (Box 54)
    - Town Meeting Conference, 1967 (Box 54)
    - Washington Newsletter, 1966-1969 (Box 54)
    - World Peace Foundation, 1967-1968 (Box 54)
  - Task forces
    - Innovation in Public Affairs Education, 1967-1968; 2 folders (Box 54)
  - Units and divisions
    - Adult Competency Education, 1982-1984 (Box 54)
    - Adult Learners with Disabilities, 1983-1984 (Box 54)
    - Aging, 1994 (Box 54)
    - Armed Services, 1986 (Box 54)
    - Business and Industry, 1983-1984 (Box 54)
    - Colleges and Universities, 1984 (Box 54)
    - Community-Based Education, 1983-1984 (Box 54)
    - Continuing Education for the Professions, 1982-1986 (Box 54)
    - Cooperative Extension Service, 1983-1985 (Box 54)
    - Correctional Institutions, 1986-1987 (Box 54)
    - Human Resource Development Practitioners, 1984 (Box 54)
    - International Adult Education, 1984-1986 (Box 54)
    - Library Services, 1985 (Box 54)
    - Life Skills Programs and Curricula, 1984-1985 (Box 54)
    - National Council of Administrators of Adult Education, 1983-1984 (Box 54)
    - Professional Development, 1982-1983 (Box 54)
    - Religious Adult Education, 1983-1984 (Box 54)
    - Special Populations and Issues, 1983 (Box 54)
    - Theory, research and Evaluation, 1982-1984 (Box 54)
    - Volunteers and Volunteerism, 1983-1985 (Box 54)
    - Women's Issues, Status and Education, 1982-1985 (Box 54)
- [Part III] Historical files
  - AAACE, 1982-1986
    - NEA-R Notebook (Box 55)
    - National Awards Breakfast for the 1989 Outstanding Adult Learner (Box 55)
    - NAEC Progress Report, 1983 (Box 55)
    - NAEC, 1983-1984; 2 folders (Box 55)
    - Budget/Financial Statements, 1985-1986 (Box 55)
    - National Adult Continuing Education Week, 1986 (Box 55)
    - Commemorative posters for AAACE, undated (Box 55)
    - AAACE Annual Report, 1983-1984 (Box 55)
    - Congressional Report, 1986 (Box 55)
    - AAACE Bylaws, undated (Box 55)
    - AETNA Institute for Corporate Educaiton, 1980 (Box 55)
    - Adult Literacy Research Conference, 1986 (Box 55)
    - Adult Literacy Initiative, 1985 (Box 55)
    - Financial review, 1986 (Box 55)
    - Strategic planning, 1986 (Box 55)
    - COABE, 1987 (Box 55)
    - Samset, Sidney, Bankers Life Insurance, 1984-1986 (Box 55)
    - AAACE Plan of Consolidation, 1982 (Box 55)
    - Airlie House Conference, 1981-1983 (Box 55)
    - Collaboration and Cooperation in Lifelong Learning, 11/4/84 (Box 55)
    - Educational Funding Committee, 1986 (Box 55)
    - Education and Training for American Competitiveness Act, 1986 (Box 55)
    - English Language Proficiency Survey, 1986 (Box 55)
    - Elections AAACE, 1984-1985 (Box 55)
    - Ellison, Art, 1986; testimony (Box 55)
    - Legal status of NEA/USA, undated (Box 55)
    - Executive Director search, 1984 (Box 55)
    - Thinking Back - Looking Forward by Robert A. Luke, 1986 (Box 55)
    - Status of Continuing Education for Selected Professions, 1986 (Box 55)
    - Statistics, 1985 (Box 55)
    - Rural Education, 1986 (Box 55)
    - Readership Survey, 1985 (Box 55)
    - National Assessment of Educational Progress (NAEP), 1985 (Box 55)
    - Mawby speech, Wisconsin, 11/85 (Box 55)
    - ICAE: A Survey of Member Organizations, 1984 (Box 55)
    - FYI, 1985; 1986; 3 folders (Box 55)
    - AAACE Conference, 1986 (Box 55)
    - Literacy Management Information (Box 55)
  - AEA